dogbreedinfo.com 2019-03-08

# Dog Breed Info Centers® - Privacy Policy

Dog Breed Info Center® (“we” or “us”) is committed to respecting your privacy. Please read the following privacy policy (“Policy”) to understand what information we collect from you, how we protect such information, and how you can choose to limit or change what information we collect. This Policy governs any services provided by Dog Breed Info Center® and the websites located at Dogbreedinfo.com and Maguirefarm.com (collectively, “DBIC”). We may provide access to DBIC through use of mobile devices, Internet web sites, or through other platforms; and with such access, you warrant and represent that you have read, understand, and agree to all terms and conditions stated herein. If you do not agree with any of the terms and conditions in this policy, do not use or access DBIC

If there is a conflict between the terms of this Policy and the Terms of Service, then this Policy shall control. If you have any questions regarding this Policy or DBIC, please [contact us](mailto:contact@dogbreedinfo.com).

Please note that this Policy only applies to DBIC. It does not apply to any information that you share with any third party or on any other external forum or communication node (for example, Twitter, Facebook, Pinterest, Google+, iMessage, a website, a blog, an e-mail, etc.) made available through DBIC. In other words, we are not responsible for the privacy practices of any entity or service that we neither own nor completely manage or control. 

#### 1.0 Revisions to this Policy

This Policy may be updated from time to time on DBIC. The actions we take with regard to collecting and sharing information are subject to the Policy posted at that time. It is your responsibility to periodically review the Policy to see recent changes. If you choose not to review any of the recent changes or are unaware of any recent changes, you agree that you accept the revised Policy.

The current version of this Policy is effective as of May 24th 2018.

#### 2.0 Consent to Collect Information

When you visit our website, we automatically collect information, including information regarding your device, IP address, and country or region (for further details, see the “Device and Location Information” section of this Privacy Policy). In addition, some of the services provided by DBIC ask a visitor to provide additional information. We require a minimum of information to be provided, which varies depending on the specific service (for further details, see the “Personally Identifiable Information Collected From You” section of this Privacy Policy). When you submit information through DBIC’s services (for example, when you submit a photo of your dog), we also automatically collect information regarding your device, IP address, and country or region. We collect this information to prevent the misuse of our services by visitors or bots, so that we can provide accurate information on DBIC’s websites.

If you wish to withdraw your consent for DBIC to collect or retain information about you or about your dog, please [contact us](mailto:contact@dogbreedinfo.com).

#### 3.0 Personally Identifiable Information Collected from You

__Information required to submit a photograph__

In order to submit a photograph of your dog to DBIC through the dogbreedinfo.com website, you must provide your first and last name as well as a valid e-mail address. You may also choose to provide your address and phone number, but this information is optional. Certain information regarding your dog is required, so that we can properly identify the dog’s breed, age and name. You may, if you wish, submit a biography of your dog.

To submit photographs, you must agree to the terms of DBIC’s Photo Submission Agreement. In the event of a conflict between the Photo Submission Agreement and this Privacy Policy, the Privacy Policy will control.

__Social Networking__

As a convenience to you, DBIC provides you with access to external communication nodes and third party social networks, such as Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest, iMessage, and others. In general, this will be through a sharing interface or link provided on one of the website’s pages. When you share information with a social networking application or site, you could disclose information (for example, your name, picture, location, friends, or other personal details) that could become public knowledge. You agree that your usage of such social networks is done at your sole risk and that we would be unable to guarantee your privacy.

We do not currently provide social networking interfaces through our site (including the ability to “like” or “share” articles). This is one way in which we limit the collection of your personal information by third parties.

#### 4.0 Device and Location Information

__Data Tracking__

We may rely on cookies, pixels, tags, beacons, local storage, and other related technology to track and retain user, device, and website activity, mainly to do the following: (a) identify the unique id numbers and IP addresses of various devices and browsers; (b) retain user activity logs, inputs, clicks, and related data; (c) analyze user preferences and behavior; and (d) help us improve our products and services. We make reasonable efforts to honor the “do not track” settings on users’ devices.

__Photographs__

DBIC allows users to submit photographs to our site. However, to provide such a feature, we will need permission to access the photographs on your computer or mobile device. If you do not grant us this permission, DBIC will not access them, and you will not be able to upload photographs.

#### 5.0 Service Information Storage and Personal Information Retention

Dogbreedinfo.com is operated by the Dog Breed Info Center®, a business located in the United States of America at 3 Crozerville Road, Aston, PA 19014. When you provide us with personal information, including your name, e-mail address and other information, you agree that we may store, process, export, or otherwise access this information on servers located outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”). You also agree that we may share your information with our business partners, vendors, or advertisers.

We will retain your information for as long as we consider necessary for the purposes stated in our Privacy Policy. We will also retain and use your information for as long as is required in order to comply with our legal obligations.

#### 6.0 How Your Information is Used

We will not sell, rent or lease your personally identifiable information to others (such as your name and e-mail address) without clearly disclosing such intentions in an updated version of this Policy. Where necessary for performing services for us, our business partners may also access that information.

As a matter of standard procedure, information submitted by you will generally be stored indefinitely on our servers. That said, if we are required by law to delete information submitted by you (such as your name, e-mail address, or photographs which you’ve submitted) from our databases, such as under the Child Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”), or if you were to make such a deletion request, we will do so.

Advertising

We do share user information with advertising partners, including Google, Inc. and its affiliated companies, such as DoubleClick. Our advertising (for example, through Google’s AdSense service) may include using third-party vendors to display our ads across the Internet. These third-party vendors may use cookies to serve ads based on your web browsing history, including your visits to DBIC websites. You can find a list of allowed third-party ads by going to [https://www.google.com/adsense/support/bin/answer.py?answer=94149&topic=14535](https://support.google.com/adsense/answer/94149?topic=14535). The third-party advertising companies that Google uses to serve ads when you visit our website may use information from your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. However, Google AdSense will not collect your name, address, email address or telephone number. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by Google AdSense, [click here](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/). 

You may opt out of Google's use of cookies by visiting [Google's Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads/authenticated) page. You may opt out of DoubleClick's use of cookies by visiting the [DoubleClick opt-out page](https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads/anonymous?sig=ACi0TCiXW8imA4UR2K4yk8fNX6rAcHrKJeGQkgyXiJ_-OqNi6rjihfoOcUMfZ49UGT_fUjKhLWZogaL-6qWlSsS_FJOo7Y3bpGwRfkYmfDD7cr-GsXnLIDQ&hl=en) or the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/).

#### 7.0 Your Rights Regarding Your Personal Information

You have the right to access, correct, or delete your personal information. To do so, please contact our Data Protection Officer at the address provided below, so that DBIC can assist you. To protect your privacy, we reserve the right to request reasonable evidence to verify your identity, before we disclose your information.

For information that we collect and which is covered by this Privacy Policy, the data controller is Dog Breed Info Center. Our Data Protection Officer can be contacted at: [contact@dogbreedinfo.com](mailto:contact@dogbreedinfo.com)

#### 8.0 Age Restrictions

DBIC is not meant to be used by anyone under age 13. If you are under age 13, you may not submit photographs to DBIC. If you are a parent of a child under age 13 who is using DBIC, please use your own name and contact information when submitting information to DBIC (for example, if you are uploading a photograph of your dog). If you have any questions, please [contact us](mailto:contact@dogbreedinfo.com).

#### 9.0 Necessary Disclosures

In situations where it is necessary to share information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, violations of the Terms of Service, or to otherwise comply with the law, we will do so. Also, where necessary in the event of a merger, consolidation, or sale of all or substantially all of our assets, we may share your information with a third party without your prior consent.

#### 10.0 Disclaimer

Notwithstanding the forgoing policies and precautions that we exercise, we expressly disclaim any liability that may arise from your provision of any information about yourself to DBIC. To this extent, you agree to hold us harmless from any liability related to your provision of personal information to DBIC. Moreover, you understand and agree, as provided by the Terms of Service, that you grant us a worldwide, non-exclusive, royalty-free license to display, copy, reproduce, publish, distribute, adapt, or modify anything to which you hold proprietary rights and which you submit to DBIC.

#### 11.0 Other Legal Notices.

Any dispute over privacy is subject to this Policy and our Terms of Service. If you have any concern about your privacy in connection with this Policy, please send us a thorough description at [contact@dogbreedinfo.com](mailto:contact@dogbreedinfo.com) and we will try to resolve it.

Last revised: 5-24-2018
